Finding Aid for President (University of Michigan) publications, 1909-2007
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
President (University of Michigan) publications 1909-2007
University of Michigan. President.
1.6 linear feet
06126 Bimu 2
The publications of the University of Michigan President and publications produced by the office record the public life of the university president and document the concerns of the university in response to current events and pressures. The records include publications from inaugurations, State of the University Addresses, letters, and event programs. The most significant records are commission findings, essays and lectures, and university reports.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Publications are received periodically from the unit (donor no. 566 ).
Periodic additions to the records expected.
The publications are open without restriction.
For historical sketch of the President's office see the finding aid for President (University of Michigan) records.
The publications of the President record the public life of the University President and document communication with the campus community and public about the concerns of the university in response to current events and pressures. The records span the years 1909 to the present, with the bulk of the collection covering the years 1985-2000.
The material includes publications from inaugurations, State of the University Addresses, letters, and event programs. The most significant publications are commission findings, essays and lectures, and university reports. These records document university investigations and responses to concerns such as women's issues and future university expansion. These publications also contain materials relating to bestowing honorary degrees, financial reports, and speeches to community organizations. Also included are some hard copy print-out examples of presidential email announcements. Some publications (or their successors) may no longer be available in print but are available on the school s website.
Subjects:
University of Michigan. President.; University of Michigan--Administration.; Tappan, Henry Philip, 1805-1881.; Angell, James Burrill, 1829-1916.; Little, Clarence C. (Clarence Cook), b. 1888.; Ruthven, Alexander Grant, 1882-1971.; Hatcher, Harlan Henthorn, 1898-; Fleming, R. W. (Robben Wright), 1916-2010.; Shapiro, Harold T., 1935-; Duderstadt, James J., 1942-; Bollinger, Lee C., 1946-; Coleman, Mary Sue.; Little, Clarence C. (Clarence Cook), b. 1888.
Contributors:
Ruthven, Alexander Grant, 1882-1971.; Hatcher, Harlan Henthorn, 1898-; Fleming, R. W. (Robben Wright), 1916-2010.; Shapiro, Harold T., 1935-; Duderstadt, James J., 1942-; Bollinger, Lee C., 1946-; Coleman, Mary Sue.; White, B. Joseph.
- Unit Publications
  - Addresses
    - Presidential Addresses and Speeches 1956-2001, 2 folders (Box 1)
    - The State of the University, 1970-1974 (Box 1)
    - State of the University Address, 1988-1989, 1993, 1995 (Box 1)
      (also includes distinguished faculty achievement awards)
  - Biographies and Inaugurations
    - Henry P. Tappan (Box 1)
    - James B. Angell (Box 1)
    - Clarence C. Little (Box 1)
    - Alexander Ruthven (Box 1)
    - Harlan Hatcher (Box 1)
    - Robben W. Fleming (Box 1)
    - Harold Shapiro (Box 1)
    - James J. Duderstadt (Box 1)
    - Lee Bollinger (Box 1)
    - Mary Sue Coleman (Box 1)
  - Brochures
    - The President's Donor Challenge: Making a Difference in Graduate and Professional Student Support, circa 2007 (Box 1)
  - Christmas cards and holiday greetings undated (Box 1)
  - Commissions
    - Citizens Committee on Higher Education 1963 (Box 1)
    - The Michigan Agenda for Women 1994-1995 (Box 1)
    - Needs of Medical Education in Michigan 1957 (Box 1)
    - The Organization of the University 1996 (Box 1)
    - President's Advisory Commission on Women's Issues 1990-1991 (Box 1)
    - The Role of the Student in Decision Making 1967 (Box 1)
    - Commission on the Undergraduate Experience 2001 (Box 1)
    - Women's Agenda for the 1990s, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Emails (hard copy print-outs)
    - Lee C. Bollinger 1998-2001 (Box 1)
    - B. Joseph White 2001-2002 (Box 1)
    - Mary Sue Coleman 2002 (Box 1)
  - Essays/Lecture Series
    - Changing in a World of Change, 1996 (Box 1)
    - Climate and Character, Perspectives on Diversity, 1997 (Box 1)
    - The Government-University Research Partnership, 1992 (Box 1)
    - The Monograph Series 1995-1996 (Box 1)
    - Presidential Lecture Series on Academic Values, 1993 (Box 1)
    - Scientific Integrity of the University, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Guides
    - A Guide to University of Michigan Activities in Metropolitan Detroit, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Invitations 1982-2006 (Box 1)
  - Letters
    - Diversity Issues 1970, 1989, 1996 (Box 1)
    - Fundraising/M-Campaign 1985-1992 (Box 1)
    - Miscellaneous 1965-1998 (Box 1)
  - Programs
    - An Afternoon with the Presidents 1992 (Box 1)
    - The Games 2000 (Box 1)
  - President's Weekends 1986-1996 (Box 2)
  - Reports
    - Enriching a Heritage of Leadership, 1982 (Box 2)
    - Financial Assets and Investments 1995-1996, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - In the Interim, 1996-1997 (Box 2)
    - A Growing Season, 1986-1996, 1996 (Box 2)
    - Michigan Agenda for Women: Toward a Full and Equal Partnership, 1995 (Box 2)
    - The Michigan Metrics, 1994-1995, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - One Year Later...Commitment to Leadership; Annual Report on Minority Affairs, 1987-1988 (Box 2)
    - President's Letters, 1968-1970 (Box 2)
    - Rebuilding the University, 1986-1996, 1996 (Box 2)
    - Report of the President, 1931-1990, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Report to the University Community, 1966-1979 (Box 2)
    - Strategic Planning for the Twenty-First Century, 1994 (Box 2)
    - A Strategy for Our Future, 1996 (Box 2)
    - Toward an Educational Transformation, 1996 (Box 2)
    - U-M Commentary, 1962 (Box 2)
    - Undergraduate Education at the University of Michigan: A Sample of Programs, 1991-1992 (Box 2)
    - University of Michigan Honorary Degrees 1996 (Box 2)
    - The University of Michigan's Media Union 1995 (Box 2)
    - A Vision for the 21st Century, 1995 (Box 2)
    - Women at the University of Michigan, volumes 1-3, 1992-1996, 2 folders (Box 2)
    - Women Lecturers in the Residential College, 1995 (Box 2)
- Archived University of Michigan President WEBSITE
  The President's Archived Website series documents the mission, activities, policies, and individuals involved in the operation of the Office of the President. Content includes important news and announcements, publications (such as reports and administrative documents), and information about committees, initiatives, and events. This archived website will be captured on a regular, ongoing basis as part of the University of Michigan Web Archives, hosted at http://webarchives.cdlib.org/a/universityofmichigan/. Prior to 2010 several snapshots of the President's website were captured locally and stored on CD. They can now be downloaded as ZIP files from Deep Blue, the university's institutional repository.
  - Archived University of Michigan President home page 2001
  - Archived University of Michigan President home page 2005
  - Archived University of Michigan President home page 2008
  - Archived University of Michigan President home page 2009
  - Archived University of Michigan President home page, 2010-[ongoing]